

Piotr Dąbrowski

One month notice

Wrocław, Poland

<u>linkedin.com/in/pidabrow</u>

DM me on LinkedIn for phone/email address

Professional Profile

Experienced Software Developer / Technical Lead from Poland with 10 years of experience in design, development and maintenance of Java-based applications, including 3 years of remote work for a Silicon Valley company in Pacific Time hours. I have full working proficiency in both English and German.

Core Skills

Backend:

- Java 11, Spring (MVC, Boot)
- JPA / Hibernate
- SQL, NoSQL, basics of PLSQL
- REST, gRPC
- Streaming architecture RabbitMQ
- Microservice architecture
- familiarity with AWS and serverless
- familiarity with DevOps-ing

Frontend:

- HTML
- JSP

Availability:

Location:

LinkedIn:

- Bootstrap
- familiarity with Javascript and JQuery
- basics of React JS

Tools:

- Git as main VCS, also SVN, CVS
- Maven / Gradle
- CI/CD (mostly Jenkins)
- Sparx Enterprise Architect
- Atlassian Toolset
- Monitoring: Sentry, Graylog
- Bitbucket, Github
- Keycloak, Kong

Experience

January 2021 - present | Technical Lead

Technical Lead for a mid-size development team. Key responsibilities:

- taking responsibility for the codebase along with its technical consistency and delivery
- implementing new features for a company associated with the pharmaceutical industry incl. analysing requirements and designing the architecture/domain model.
- cooperation with the PO for the project
- taking care of the infrastructure
- preparing releases to production from a technical standpoint (incl. technical documentation and release procedures)

Tech stack: Java 11, Spring, Hibernate, Postgres, Oracle (data warehouse), MongoDB, RabbitMQ

November 2019 - December 2020 | Senior Java Developer @Epam Systems

Tech stack: Java 11, gRPC, Go, Angular, Javascript, JUnit, Spring, Hibernate

Implementing and maintaining internal tools for Google Fiber (as an external vendor), working on tools for internal purposes.

I was also a technical interviewer on behalf of the Company with over 20 interviews completed.

September 2016 - October 2019 | Senior Full Stack Developer @Sunbasket Inc.

As a senior full stack developer for one of the trending meal kit delivery companies in the US, I'm responsible for design, coding and maintenance of the web application and the REST API for mobile apps.

Tech stack: Java 8, Spring, Hibernate, JSP, HTML5, Bootstrap, JQuery, Javascript, AWS, MySQL.

January 2015 - September 2016 | Senior Software Engineer @Capgemini

Lead developer for two out of six business modules in a project for an insurance company from Germany, including regular contact with the customer and workshops in customer's HQ in Munich. **Tech stack:** Java 6/8, Java EE, Quasar, Oracle Databases, Web services.

January 2013 - December 2014 | Software Engineer @Capgemini March 2012 - December 2012 | Junior Software Engineer @Capgemini November 2011 - February 2012 | Trainee @Capgemini

Education

2012-2013 Master of Science - Computer Science @Wrocław University of Technology **2008-2012** Bachelor of Science - Computer Science @Wrocław University of Technology

Visas & Permissions

Polish passport, US Visa B-1/B-2, driving license.

Hobbies

Cars, stock market and investing, history

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realising the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation)".